# Vijayakumar Bangaru

Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu vijayakumarb96\_wxd@indeedemail.com +91 99442 56090

I am a responsible, creative and hands on technical support with more than 5 years of experience operating system (Windows).

Qualified to IT industry standards, myself updating and tracking the latest technologies and apply them to my duties wherever possible.

#### TECHNOLOGY STACK

Tools: AnyDesk and Teamviewer

Package: MS Office(Excel functions V lookup, H lookup and pivot table)

# Work Experience

## Sr.Field Technician

**Retail Shops** 

October 2020 to Present

#### **ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITY**

- Maintains reports of and hands to the senior and concerned
- Remote desktop connection and Remote assistance
- Providing technical support for day to day work
- Installation and implementation of desktop computing devices, printers and other peripheral devices, and wireless computing and communications devices.
- · Working of and experience in the Financial Services industry and its regulations
- Performs other duties assigned.
- Work with individuals in a virtual, multi-vendor and multi-cultural environment with different level of technical understanding; should be able to adjust communication style based on targeted audience
- · Analyse customer needs, document requirements, and design technical solutions.

# WORK EXPERIENCE [Sr.Service Engineer]

2) Company: Aurionpro Solutions Ltd Web site: www.aurionpro.com

## Company Description:

Aurionpro Solutions Limited is a global technology solutions company. The Company is engaged in offering information technology (IT) and consultancy services. It is also engaged in the sale of equipment and software licenses. It is engaged in the business of providing solutions in corporate banking, treasury, fraud prevention and risk management, Internet banking, governance and compliance. Its geographic segments include India. It is a provider of intellectual property-led IT solutions for the banking and financial service insurance segments. It also provides self-service technologies, which enable financial institutions, utilities, telecom and government organization.

# **Sr.Service Engineer**

Banking and financial service insurance segments - Delhi, Delhi August 2015 to October 2020

#### **ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITY**

- CCTV Installation and Configuration (Working in Delhi CCTV GOVT project)
- Co-ordinate With Field Engineers and Add the IP Camera's details in CCC Server(Central Command Center PWD office)
- Data Backup and Restoration Procedures
- Helps in the installation process of new and advanced technologies interpreting the requirements
- Give the Training to the bank person about Self-service Kiosk
- Managing any kind of technical work at the field even with little supervision
- Ability to communicate fluently with the customers and should possess good customer service skills
- Maintaining Incident report system during System downtime
- · Networking and crimping
- Network and TCP/IP Configuration and Troubleshooting
- Remote desktop connection and Remote assistance
- Providing technical support for day to day Banking
- Maintains reports of and hands to the senior and concerned

3) Company: BILDScribe BPO India Pvt Ltd Web site: http://www.bildscribe.com

#### Company Description:

BILDScribe BPO India Pvt Ltd is the domestic call centre that provides inbound & outbound process, data entry process and English language academy. We deliver data processing, inbound process for one of the leading telecom industry.

#### Project 1:

#### **Desktop support Administrator**

English language academy (Outbound Process) May 2014 to July 2015

#### **ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITY**

- Managed over 150 PCs in a Windows environment
- Configured PCs to be joined to local area networks and domains
- Installation and configuration of Windows XP, Windows 7, Windows 8, Windows 8.1
- Troubleshooting software and hardware related concerns
- Disk management and partition
- Folder sharing and mapping into drive
- Followed specific internal design specifications and met specific deadlines

## **Desktop Support Administrator**

Aircel (Inbound Process)
July 2013 to July 2015

#### **ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITY**

- Hardware Maintenance and Replacement
- Windows Operating System Installations: Windows XP, Windows Vista, and Windows 7

- Windows Operating System Configurations and Troubleshooting
- Network and TCP/IP Configuration and Troubleshooting
- Printer Installation and configuring network printers
- Basic networking and crimping
- Troubleshooting internet and intranet systems
- Remote desktop connection and Remote assistance
- Antivirus installation on client and server end
- $\bullet$  Providing solutions to the day to day problems of the users

Project 2:

# Education

#### BE

Tamilnadu College of Engineering, Anna University Coimbatore - Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu 2009 to 2013

# **HSC**

N.S.Boys Hr. Sec School - Teni, Tamil Nadu 2008 to 2009

#### **SSLC**

N.S.Boys Hr. Sec School - Teni, Tamil Nadu 2006 to 2007

# Skills / IT Skills

• Operating Systems: Windows -Windows XP/Vista/7/8/8.1/10